# **Adrian Salgado**

hola@lasfi.to

GitHub.com/lasfito

LinkedIn.com/in/lasfito



Software Engineer with **4+ years** of experience in web development (frontend / backend) and mobile development. Proficient in JavaScript, TypeScript, Node, React, and React Native; Intermediate in Go. Beyond his professional role, he actively engages in technology through an independent SaaS project and the creation of development tutorials on YouTube.

### **Experience**

**Senior Software Engineer** 

Money Forward (Japan)

Nov 2023 - Current

• Developed and maintained a web application focused on financial and banking services. Emotion, Git, JavaScript, React, React, Redux, TypeScript.

# Software Engineer II

Honeywell (USA remote)

May 2022 - Feb 2023

- Participated in the building of an enterprise micro-frontend SPA through federated modules.
- Devised and conducted test plans to ensure 95%+ code coverage through unit testing.
- Actively participated in sprint grooming, planning & code review with a 100% say-do ratio.
  Git, JavaScript, Jest, Jira, React, Serverless, Redux, RTK Query, StoryBook, Styled Components, Tailwind, TypeScript.

# **Software Engineer**

LATAVAL (Mexico)

Nov 2021 - April 2022

- Lead the architecture and development of a mobile App (React Native) with over 5k MAU.
- Set up production-facing REST API endpoints to handle a peak of 1,000 requests per second.
- Developed an internal CMS by leveraging Google Cloud Platform and CI/CD pipelines.

AWS, CSS3, Docker, Expo, Express.js, Google Cloud, Linux, Next.js, Node.js, React.js, React Native, Remix, Strapi.

## **Software Developer**

7iete Studio (Mexico)

July 2020 - Oct 2021

- Created performant (1s load) websites by leveraging SSR/SSG UI frameworks through Jamstack.
- Developed cross-platform (Android/iOS) apps with great UX as measured by 27% user retention.
- Enhanced an internal dashboard for dataviz by 25% as measured by loading performance.
- Implemented a real-time chat functionality resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- Optimized ecommerce checkout process, reducing cart abandonment rates by 15%.

Express, Firebase, Gatsby, GraphQL, GitHub, MUI, Netlify, Next, Node, OOP, PWA, React, React Native, Sass, WordPress.

#### Web Developer

CEMERI (Mexico)

Sept 2019 - July 2020

- Built an academic search engine through Google API that was in use by over 10K students.
- Designed an internal tool for map creation (d3.js) which boosted publishing rate by 33%.
- Mapped and enhanced the SEO architecture with monthly increments of 15% impressions.
- Migrated website from self-hosted WordPress installation into Headless + cloud CMS CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Google Tag Manager, HTML, XML, Wordpress.

#### **Projects**

**AxoGo** Mobile App for Japanese learning (Kanji/Vocab) through mnemonics and SRS *Expo, Firebase, React Native, React Native Skia, Redux.* 

» iOS

**Xolo SEO** SaaS that leverages NLP/AI to improve SEO performance » XoloSeo.com FastAPI, Firebase, GCP, HuggingFace, Playwright, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Python, Railway, React, Remix, SQL.

YouTube Content Creation Software Development tutorials

» YouTube.com/@lasfito

#### Education

BA International Relations from UNAM (Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México)

**Language Certificates:** C1 English O A2 Russian O N5 Japanese